你可没说戒备会这么森严
- You didn't say there'd be such security.
他们把下午班机提早到了
- They moved the flight forward.
我们还是得按计划进行
We'll have to go ahead as planned anyway.
托洛？听来好像蛮牛
Toro? Sounds like a load of bull.
詹姆斯
James.
小心一点
Be careful.
也界可真小  你也叫托洛
Well, small world. You're a Toro, too.
迈阿密见
l'll see you in Miami.
（燃料不足）
请加满油
Fill her up.
（东柏林）
（英国大使官邸）
大使  宾客都到了
Your guests have arrived, Ambassador.
亲爱的  该去迎宾了
We should go, my dear.
Well...
你越来越漂亮了
You become more beautiful every day.
- 我在这里 - 当然是
- l'm over here. - Of course you are.
她是我的新助理 潘娜普斯摩本小姐
This is Miss Penelope Smallbone, my new assistant.
斯摩本小姐 钱班霓  我能说什么…
Miss Smallbone.What can l say, Moneypenny?
除了她又漂亮又迷人
Except that she is as attractive and as charming...
- 跟我从前一样？ - 我可没说
- As l used to be? - l didn't say that.
詹姆斯  你真会奉承
You're such a flatterer, James.
钱班霓  你也知道 从来没有人…
Moneypenny, you know there never has been
以后也没人能像你这样吸引我
and never will be anybody but you.
你已经说过了
So you've told me.
- 欢迎加入环球出口公司 - 收下吧  亲爱的
- Welcome to Universal Exports. - Take it, dear.
那是你唯一能从他身上得到的
- That's all you'll ever get from him.
- 谢谢  邦德指挥官 - 你认识我？
- Thank you, Commander Bond.- Do you know me?
钱班霓小姐形容过你
- Miss Moneypenny described you.
详细到令人厌恶
ln nauseating detail.
真的？
Really?
你一定很适合在这工作的
l can see you're going to fit in here very nicely.
- 早安  007 - 早安  长官
- Good morning, 007. - Morning, sir.
- 部长 - 指挥官
- Minister. - Commander.
你应该认识吉姆芬宁 我们的艺术品专家
l think you know Jim Fanning, our art expert.
- 是的  你好  吉姆 - 詹姆斯
- Yes. Hello, Jim. - James.
- 你知道这是什么？ - 看来像法贝燮的珠宝蛋
- Do you know what this is? - lt looks like a Faberg?egg, sir.
卡尔法贝燮制作的珠宝蛋之一
One of the jewelled eggs by Carl Faberg?
当作俄国皇室的复活节礼物
as a gift for the Russian royal family.
价值连城而且相当稀少
They're priceless and very rare.
这个里面有座 皇家马车的模型
This one contains a model of the imperial state coach.
- 叙述的真详细  007 - 谢谢你  长官
- Top marks, 007. - Thank you, sir.
只不过这是膺品
Except it's a fake.
这个才是真品
There's the real thing.
今天下午将在苏富比拍卖
lt's being auctioned at Sotheby's this afternoon.
这是今年拍卖的第四个珠宝蛋
This is the fourth egg to turn up at auction this year.
不是经由正常管道  匿名的卖主
lt's from none of the usual sources. Anonymous seller,
秘密瑞士银行帐户
Swiss bank account.
我敢说卖主是俄国人
l'd say that the vendor was a Russian.
这个变成为…
And now this turns up.
几可乱真的膺品
A near-perfect forgery.
我认为邦德应陪你去拍卖会
l think Commander Bond should accompany you to the sale.
太好了  我正需要帮手
Splendid. l could use an extra pair of eyes.
或许我们能找出卖主是谁
We could try and spot the seller.
他们通常都表现得毫无兴趣
They usually turn up out of interest
或是趁机哄抬物价
or perhaps just to bump up the price.
谢谢你  芬宁
Thank you, Fanning.
不客气
Not at all.
如果俄国人是卖主 有可能是筹措财源
lf it is the Russians, it may be an effort to raise currency
为海外间谍活动提供经费 或是偿还债务
for covert operations abroad or for payoffs.
无论如何 我们最好查明他们的企图
Either way, we'd better find out what they're up to.
是  部长
- Yes, Minister. - Eyes only, 007.
007  机密文件  宝物行动
Operation Trove.
你取代009进行任务
You'll be replacing 009.
他在东德因公殉职
He turned up dead in East Germany
手中还握着那个珠宝蛋
with that egg in his hand.
- 我恐怕没进一步的线索 - 部长  还有一条线索
There's not much to go on. Well, we do have one lead, Minister.
「一位女士的收藏」
''Property of a Lady.''
下一项议题是…
Next on the agenda is the continuing
与北约组织的双边限武谈判
mutual disarmament talks with NATO.
我想你们都看过戈格将军的报告
l assume you've all read General Gogol's report.
内容似乎非常详尽
lt seems very thorough.
谢谢你  主席同志
Thank you, Comrade Chairman.
我相信我已表达给在座各位了
l believe l express the opinion of everyone present
采纳北约组织的建议
that adoption of NATO proposals does
并不会危害我们的国防体系
not compromise our defensive position.
主席同志
- Comrade Chairman.
奥洛夫将军
- General Orlov.
戈格将军太放肆了
General Gogol is presumptuous.
他只代表自己…
He speaks for himself and others
及其他贪生怕死的人发言
who cling to timid, outdated
落伍且不切实际的政策
and unrealistic policies.
难道要我提醒各位
Must l remind you, the committee,
在决定限武谈判之前
of our overwhelming superiority over NATO forces
我们对北约组织有绝对的优势？
before we give it away?
我在东德地区所指挥的部队
ln East Germany under my direct command,
共有31个师的兵力
l have 31 divisions, including 1 1 tank divisions
包括11个装甲师 捷克另有五个装甲师
and another five in Czechoslovakia.
支援西部边境的还有六十个师
ln support, on the Russian western border are 60 divisions,
包括22个装甲师
including 22 tank divisions.
总言之  我军的优势是十比一
ln all, a 10-1 advantage.
美国与西德军方顶多…
American and West German forces
只能动员十个装甲师
can field at most ten armoured divisions.
英国只维持象征性的兵力
The British maintain only a token force.
我们运用最新型的科索夫电脑
We have played out a variety of attack
已进行多次进攻战略沙盘推演
strategies on the new Kutuzov computer
结论就是以十个装甲师…
and find that a lightning thrust by
向北方发动闪电攻势
ten armoured divisions from the north,
再加上五个装甲师取道捷克
and by five more through Czechoslovakia,
面对任何可能遭遇的防御
lead to total victory in five days
我军五天便可获致全面胜利
against any possible defence scenario.
这简直太疯在了！ 我们都知道这么做的结果
This is absolute madness. We know where it will end.
北约组织会以核武反击
NATO will counterattack with nuclear weapons.
绝对不会！
Never.
西方也界是颓废分化的
The West is decadent and divided.
他们不敢冒我方核子报复的危险
lt has no stomach to risk our atomic reprisals.
整个欧洲地区  每天都有人示威
Throughout Europe, daily demonstrations
要求片面核武限制
demand unilateral nuclear disarmament.
我看不出为何要甘冒战争危险
l see no reason to risk war
来满足你个人的偏执狂
to satisfy your personal paranoia
以及征服他人的野心
and thirst for conquest.
我们必须先解决国内迫切的问题
We must turn our energies to pressing domestic problems.
- 戈格将军  让我提醒你 - 同志们  坐下
- General Gogol, let me remind you... - Comrades, sit down.
- 我要告诉你… - 你们两个都坐下
- l wish to tell you... - Both of you.
全球社会主义的目标要和平达成
World socialism will be achieved peaceably.
我们的军事角色是防卫性的
Our military role is strictly defensive.
奥洛夫将军  明白吗？
ls that understood, General Orlov?
戈格将军  请继续？
General Gogol, would you continue?
谢谢你  主席同志  接下来…
Thank you, Comrade Chairman.
我要说明我的报告重点
l will now turn to the specifics of my report...
告诉他我会尽快赶去
Tell him l will be there as quickly as possible.
是  将军
（克里姆林宫艺术品收藏库）
拜托！…
Please. Please.
- 我正试着专心 - 蓝金！
- l am trying to concentrate. - Lenkin.
- 到底什么事？ - 坏消息  将军同志
- What is it? - lt's terrible news, Comrade General.
复制品在运送迷中遭窃
The reproduction has been stolen in transit.
窃贼已消灭  但珠宝蛋遗失河中
The thief was dealt with, but the egg was lost in the river.
你的无能会害死大家
Your incompetence will destroy us all.
我们再制作一个
- We'll have a replacement made.
没时间了  将军同志
- There is no time, Comrade General.
我刚接获通知 两天后就要不定期盘点
l have just been informed of an unscheduled inventory in two days.
蓝金  克制点！
Control yourself.
我会通知伦敦的人员 一定要拿回真品
l'll tell our London people we must have the genuine egg back.
希望能及时联络上他们
l hope we can reach them in time.
布索尼得标
Sold to Busoni.
下一件是48号
The next lot is number 48.
名匠卡尔法贝燮为皇室制作的 纯金复活节珠宝蛋
A superb green-gold lmperial Easter egg by Carl Faberg?
透明绿的珐琅
Enamelled in translucent green,
用金打造的月挂冠叶片围烧
enclosed by gold laurel-leaf trellis.
点缀蓝宝石及镶钻的纯金四色堇
Set with blue sapphires and four petalled gold flowers with diamonds.
- 价值多少？ - 25万至30万英镑
- How much should it fetch? - ?50-300,000.
再高的话就疯了
Anything more'd be crazy.
俄国沙皇尼古拉斯 1897年在莫斯科曾使用过
..used by Tsar Nicholas in 1897 in Moscow.
「一位女士的收藏」
Property of a Lady.
这里女士可真不少
Well, there are quite a few ladies here.
她不需要亲自来
She wouldn't have to be here in person.
可以委托代理人出面
She could be represented by proxy.
底价15万英镑开始出价
l'll start it at ? 50,000.
15万  16万
1 50, 60.
17万？17万
170. 170.
18万、19万、20万
180, 190.200.
女士  出价高过你的 还有人要出价吗？
Against you, madam.- Any more?
那边有位女士
- Now there is a lady.
22万  24万英镑
?20,000. 240.
多注意拍卖状况
James, stick to the business in hand.
26万  28万英镑
?60,000. 280.
30万英镑
300,000.
接下来加价以两万镑为单位
And 20?
先生  你要出价吗？
Are you bidding, sir?
32万镑  新的出价人
?20,000. New bidder.
这可真是有趣
- That's interesting.
- 你认识他吗？ - 卡马汗
- You know him? Kamal Khan.
通常是卖主身分
Usually a seller.
来历不明的素质 勉强跻身上流人士
Marginal quality from dubious sources.
38万镑 中间的男士出价40万镑
?80,000.- 400 in the centre.
- 应该可以成交了 - 还有吗？
- Well, that should do it.
- 卡马汗出了最高价 - 先生  你出价40万镑
- Kamal has gone over the top. - Your bid, sir. 400,000.
40万镑  还有人出价吗？
400,000. Any more?
42万5千镑  新出价者
425. New bidder.
谢谢你  先生
Thank you, sir.
- 42万5千镑 - 你疯了吗？
- 425. - Have you gone mad?
看看他到底多想买它
Let's see how badly he wants it.
45万镑
450?
45万镑 有人出47万5千镑吗？
450. 475?
目前出价是45万镑 有人出47万5千镑吗？
The bid is 450. 475?
先生  有人出价比你高
Against you, sir.
有人比45万镑高吗？
No more than 450.
- 吉姆？ - 目前出价是45万镑
- Jim? - The bid is ?50,000.
有人出价47万5千镑
l have 475.
50万镑
?00,000.
有人出价50万镑  还有吗？
l have half a million pounds. All done?
还有人出价吗？
Any more?
先生  成交  50万镑
Yours, sir, for ?00,000.
一下一件是49号 - 你差点就要掏腰包买下来
- The next lot is... - We could have been stuck with it.
- 我很怀疑  他势在必得 - 为什么？
- l doubt it. He had to buy it. - But why?
这就是我要追查的原因
That's what l intend to find out.
你无权出价买那个珠宝蛋
You had no business bidding for that egg.
万一你真的出价成功该怎么办？
What would you have done if you'd got it?
我会声称那是膺品并拒绝付钱
l would have claimed it was a fake, sir, and not paid.
拒绝付钱？
Not paid?
真品在我手上
Here's the original.
我在拍卖会上调了包
l switched it with the fake during the auction.
天啊
Good God.
万一买主发现怎么办？
And what happens when the buyer discovers that?
如果他是正当的话 他会提出申诉
Well, he complains. lf he's legitimate.
- 此话怎讲？ - 我认为他不会这么做
- Well? - l don't think he will complain.
芬宁表示卡马汗通常是卖主身分
According to Fanning, this Kamal usually sells. Now he buys.
但是现在他成为买主 膺品会令他原形毕露
l believe that the fake will smoke him out.
我方人员跟踪他到希斯罗机场 他搭机前往新德里
Our tail followed him to Heathrow where he caught a plane to Delhi.
你也要去那里
You must go there, too.
我会通知沙鲁丁继续监视他
l'll alert Sadruddin, our man in Station l, to keep him under surveillance.
搭下一班飞机去
- Book yourself on the next flight out.
飞机还有55分钟就要起飞了
- Well, l've 55 minutes to catch it, sir.
- 邦德 - 是  长官？
- Oh, Bond? - Sir?
离开前先签一张珠宝蛋的放行条
Sign a chit for that egg before you go.
它现在是政府财产了
lt's government property now.
是的  长官
Of course, sir.
这首曲子真不错
Charming tune. You do take English money?
- 你收英镑吗？ - 只收一镑的金币
Only gold sovereigns.
麻烦你
Please.
我叫维杰 环球出口公司特别督导员
l'm Vijay. Special expediter, Universal Exports.
欢迎来印度  邦德指挥官 - 谢谢  叫我詹姆斯
- Welcome to lndia, Commander Bond. - Call me James.
- 好的 - 沙鲁丁在哪里？
- Where's Sadruddin? - Waiting in the taxi.
这边请  他在计程车中等待 这种乔装法大错特错 - 我讨厌蛇 - 先生  计程车
This was the wrong cover. l hate snakes.
计程车  请坐
Taxi. Please be comfortable.
- 我是沙鲁丁  地区小队长 - 你好吗？
- l am Sadruddin, Head of Section. - How do you do?
我已在新尼瓦斯饭店订好房间
- l booked you in at the Shivnivas Hotel. - Good. My luggage?
- 很好  行李呢？ - 先送去了
Gone ahead.
你能告诉我关于卡马汗的事吗？
What can you tell me about Kamal Khan?
遭放逐的阿富汗王子  运动家
Exiled Afghan prince. Sportsman -
马球、板球、网球 我也会玩一点网球
polo, cricket, tennis.- l play a bit myself.
- 真的？ - 事实上…
- Really? As a matter of fact,
我在他的俱乐部兼任职业选手
l've got a part-time job as a pro at Kamal's club.
- 那你学到了些什么？ - 我的反手拍进步了
- What have you learned so far? - My backhand's improved.
卡马汗的豪宅就在山上
Kamal lives there on the hill.
季风皇宫  那里戒备森严
The Monsoon Palace. lt's heavily guarded.
- 要如何才能找到他？ - 几乎每天下午与晚上…
- How do l get to him?
他都在饭店赌场内玩双陆棋
- He plays backgammon at the hotel.
身为饭店房客  你自然就是会员
As a guest, you're automatically a member.
- 我们何不晚一点在那里碰面？ - 我去换件轻便的衣服
- Let's meet there later. - l'll change into something less casual.
拿去  你玩蛇时可能需要它
Here, you may need this to play with your asp.
- 谢谢 - 早安
- 早安 - 我是邦德
Good morning. Name's Bond.
- 我已订好房间 - 本饭店正等你大驾光临
l believe you have a reservation. - We've been expecting you.
- 很好 - 祝你在此玩得愉快
- Good. l hope you have a pleasant stay.
我确定我会的
l'm sure l will.
谢谢
Thank you.
你的行李已整理好
Your luggage has been unpacked, sir.
谢谢
- Oh, thank you.
假如还有需要我服务之处… 有任何需要吗？
- lf l can be of further assistance... - Anything at all?
或许晚一点？
- Maybe later.
- 他玩的如何？ - 上校也不是生手
- How's he doing? - The Major's no novice.
但是卡马汗已赢了他二十万卢比
- But Kamal has won 200,000 rupees.
这你可赢不了了吧
- You'll have a job beating this.
我今天手气很好  要加倍吗？
l feel lucky. Shall we double?
当然好
Of course.
两万卢比
20,000 rupees.
该死！每次你要的时候都出豹子
- Always a double six when you need it.
- 一向如此 - 你怎么办到的？
- Always. - How do you do it.
- 全凭手腕功夫 - 我就办不到
- lt's all in the wrist. - lt's hopeless.
上校  相同赌注再玩一局如何？
- Shall we have another game, Major?- Same stake?
好  再赌一局 你的好运总会用完的
- Yes, l'll have another go. Your luck's got to run out some time.
我能一起喝一杯吗？
May l join you?
苏富比拍卖会  五十万镑？
Sotheby's. Half a million pounds?
你就是拍卖会上那个人
- The man at the auction. - Precisely.
- 没错 - 你对脸孔的记忆不错
You have a good memory for faces.
还有身材
And figures.
这一定不是巧合
- This can't be a coincidence. - No.
- 不是  你要喝些什么？ - 不  谢谢你
- What will you have? - Nothing, thank you.
或许下一次？
Some other time, perhaps?
谢谢
Thank you.
六点和一点  应该赢定了
Six and one.
- 战果如何？ - 看来上校似乎会赢
- Well? - Looks like the Major has got him.
上校  何不玩更刺激点？
Why don't we make it interesting, Major?
加注至十万卢比如何？
Double to 100,000 rupees.
我无法接受  你运气太好了
l can't accept. Not with your luck.
你赢了
You win.
换作我就会接受赌注
l would have taken that double, myself.
你何不接替上校的位子  贵姓？
Then why don't you take over the Major's position? Mr...?
邦德
Bond.
詹姆斯邦德 谢谢你  我非常乐意
James Bond. Thank you, l'd be delighted.
赌注是十万卢比
100,000 rupees, then.
六六大顺  毕竟这不是…
Double six.
一个容易被接受的六六大顺 对不对？
Not such a good double to accept, after all, was it?
我再加倍
- Double. - Of course.
没问题  你要掷一对六点才能赢
You can only win with a double six.
赌注是二十万卢比
The stake is 200,000 rupees.
你有现金吗？
Do you have the cash?
我想这个应该就足够了
Well, l think that this should be ample security.
你说对不对？
Don't you?
请开始  邦德先生
Play, Mr Bond.
你需要十足的好运气才行
You'll need a great deal of luck to get out of this.
对了  好运气
Oh, luck?
那我应该沾玩家的光
Well, then l shall use player's privilege,
借用你的骰子
and use your lucky dice.
全凭手腕功夫
lt's all in the wrist.
六六大顺
Double sixes.
真想不到
Fancy that.
二十万卢比
200,000 rupees.
我比较喜欢现金
l prefer cash.
- 兑换现金给他 - 是  先生
- Get it cashed for him. - Yes, sir.
邦德先生  快把钱花完
Spend the money quickly, Mr Bond.
我正有此意  卡马汗
l intend to, Kamal Khan.
我的保障
My security.
还有你的
And yours?
不全然是手腕的功夫
lt's not really in the wrist, you know.
- 要我跟踪他们吗？ - 你是应该…
- Should l be following them? - Yes,
不过我认为他们会跟着这个来
but l think they'll be following this.
- 谢谢 - 维杰会从此接手
Thank you.Vijay will take you from here.
我留下来继续查他的底细
l'll see if l can find out more about Kamal.
好的  拿一下好吗？
Good. Hold on to these, will you?
够你买好几个礼拜咖哩  对吧？
Keep you in curry for a few weeks, won't it?
谢谢你
Thank you.
这笔不义之财真棒
lt's a wonderful racket, this.
- 维杰  我们有伴了 - 没问题  这是公司的车
- Vijay, we have company. - No problem. This is a company car.
冲上去！
Step on it.
应该能把他们甩了
This should shake 'em off.
多亏这笔现款
Thank God for hard currency.
球赛结束  坐稳了  詹姆斯
Game, set and match. Hang on, James.
头低下！
Keep your head down.
谢谢
Thank you.
（滚下我的床）
Get off my bed.
来  接住
Here. Catch.
借用一下
Excuse me.
谢谢  你最好自己把这吞回去
Thank you. You'd better stick this back yourself.
詹姆斯！在这里  快上车
James, over here. Come on.
维杰  我给你的钱
Vijay. The money l gave you.
拿去  钞票…
Here. Rupees!
来得容易花得快
Easy come, easy go.
- 这广告还真派上用场 - 詹姆斯  这边走
lt pays to advertise. This way, James.
Q ! Ah, Q.
- 你好吗？ - 007  都是你  我很不高兴
- How are you? - Most unhappy, 007, thanks to you.
我要如何维持 工作上的高品质？
How can l be expected to maintain the quality of my work?
一接获命令就要立刻赶来 没有适合的设备
Sent out here at a moment's notice.
你不会刚好有细一点的线吧？
Have you any smaller thread?
有人把我的西装刺破了
Someone stuck a knife in my wallet.
他们没刺中  真可惜
Pity they missed you.
凯伦  麻烦你  好吗？
Karen, see to that, will you?
我把PPK手枪也弄丢了
l've also mislaid my PPK.
- 还有吗？ - 没了  就这些事
- Anything else? - No, that's all.
该死！
Blast.
Q  你无法让它挺举吗？
Having problems keeping it up, Q?
还在实验阶段
Experimental model.
- 史密特  你好 - 指挥官
- Hello, Smithers. - Commander.
- 了不起  Q - 来  我有几样东西给你
- Smashing, Q. - Come on. l have a few things for you.
史密特  非常好
Very nice, Smithers.
Q  追踪器好了吗？
ls the homing device ready yet?
不只是追踪器
Not only a homing device,
还有一具精密的麦克风
but an extremely delicate microphone as well.
像这样放进去
lt goes in there like that.
这是一支钢笔  转动一下笔套
Now, take a fountain pen. Twist the top,
内含高浓度的王水
and a highly concentrated mixture of nitric and hydrochloric acid.
- 能够溶解所有金属 - 非常适合用来毒死作家
- Dissolves all metals. - Wonderful for poison-pen letters.
007  专心点
Pay attention, 007.
将项端拔下来
Pull the top off the pen.
用这个高灵敏度的耳机
With this ultrasensitive earpiece,
可以收听窃听器的声音
you can listen in on the bug.
这个追踪器正好…
The homing device is compatible with
与你手表上的无线电测向仪匹配
the radio directional finder in your watch.
如果你还没有丢掉的话
lf you haven't lost it.
Q  好惊人  它真的有用
That's amazing, Q. lt does work.
那是什么？
What's that?
是最新型的液晶电视
That's the latest liquid-crystal TV.
真灵巧
Very handy.
Q  好美的画面
Perfect image, Q.
007  你真是的
Really, 007.
我可没时间陪你玩幼雅的游戏
Look, l haven't time for these adolescent antics.
指挥官  我们尽力了
- lt's the best we can do.
- 非常好  谢谢 - 快走吧  去办你的事
- lt's beautiful. Thank you. Go on, get along.
- 我还有事要做 - Q  我来帮你
l've got my work to do. - l'll give you a hand, Q.
- 谢谢 - 别忘了这个
- Thank you. Don't forget this.
- 谢谢你  维杰 - 别让他教坏你
Don't let him teach you any of his bad habits.
- 邦德先生  你的位子准备好了 - 我并没有订位
Mr Bond, your table is ready.- l didn't reserve one.
你的客人在等你
- Your guest is waiting, sir.
这边请
This way, please.
谢谢
Thank you.
你改变心意了
You changed your mind.
- 我很高兴 - 是吗？
- l'm glad. - Are you?
这样说好了
Well, let's put it this way.
目前为止  你是卡马汗的朋友中
So far, you are the least lethal and
最不具危险性而且最漂亮的
by far the prettiest of Kamal's friends.
谢谢你
Thank you.
是他有所提议还是你？
So does he have a proposition for me, or do you?
他提出一项交易
He suggests a trade.
用珠宝蛋换你的小命
The egg for your life.
我听说珠宝蛋的价格已飒涨 但这不是贵了一点吗？
l'd heard the price of eggs was going up, but isn't that a little high?
记帐入几号房？
Charge it to Room...?
是  27号房
Oh, 27. Along with the champagne, l suppose?
- 我想还有香槟 - 我留在接待处好了
l'll leave it at the desk.
你不介意吗？
You don't mind?
为什么？ 卡马汗已经忘了我的长相？
Why? Has Kamal forgotten what l look like already?
是我自己要的
lt's for me.
这么说来  万一我突然死了
So that if l depart this world suddenly,
你就有照片可以怀念我？
you'll have something to remember me by?
差不多
Something like that.
我保存在剪贴簿里
lt's for my scrapbook.
我收集回忆
l collect memories.
那我们就来制造些回忆吧
Well, let's get on with making a few.
我还再要一杯
l need refilling.
你当然要
Of course you do.
- 我再去拿一瓶 - 不用了
l'll get some more.
来个交杯酒
Don't bother. We'll make yours a loving cup.
好主意
What a good idea.
请原谅我的好奇  那是什么？
Forgive my curiosity, but what is that?
那是我的小章鱼
That's my little octopussy.
早安
Good morning.
早安  我不想吵醒你
Morning. l didn't want to wake you.
既然你醒了 就可以好好的说再见了
But since you're up, l can say a proper goodbye.
几点了？
What is the time?
风景真美  对不对？
Beautiful view, isn't it?
我不知如何说再见
- l don't know how to say goodbye. - Actions speak louder than words.
- 坐而言不如起而行 - 一点不错
So right.
一、二
ln. Out.
女孩们  划快点  一  二
Come on, girls. ln. Out.
收浆
Check oars.
珠宝蛋已失而复得
The egg has been recovered.
- 你应该感到高兴 - 它一被偷走后…
You should be pleased.l'm not pleased
我就很不高兴
it was stolen in the first place.
更别提这窃贼还敢把它带来这里
Nor that the thief knows enough to bring it here.
显然他是个冒险家 可能是想勒索我们
He's obviously an adventurer with possible blackmail on his mind.
反正我已经将他抓到我的皇宫
Anyway, l have him as my guest at the Monsoon Palace.
他很快就会招出所知道的一切
And he will tell us all he knows very quickly.
- 他是谁？ - 一个英国人
- Who is he? - Englishman.
喜欢珠宝蛋 特别偏爱法贝燮的作品
Likes eggs. Preferably Faberg?
还有骰子  尤其是灌铅的
And dice. Preferably loaded.
他叫詹姆斯邦德
His name is James Bond.
- 把他带来 - 他很危险
Bring him here.He's dangerous.
等他一招供就要马上除掉他
After he's talked, we must get rid of him immediately.
No.
我想你大概是不会改变心意
A ''no'' from you has little chance of becoming a ''yes''.
所以谈话到此结束
l assume, therefore, that the meeting is over.
但是你犯了一个大错
But you're making a serious mistake.
到目前我还无法抱怨服务品质
Well, so far l can't complain about the valet service.
八点用晚餐
Dinner. 8 o'clock.
邦德先生  晚安
- Good evening, Mr Bond. - Good evening.
- 晚安 - 充分休息了吗？
Well rested?
我相信你与玛格达小姐已见过了
l believe you and Miss Magda have met.
我真是三生有幸
- lt was a pleasure.
你太客气了
- You're too kind.
介意先用餐吗？
You don't mind if we start?
蛋奶酥可不能再等了
The souffl?can't wait.
请恕我在晚餐上冒昧请问
At the risk of appearing to be making light dinner conversation,
我为何会在这里？
may l ask exactly why l am here?
我是说你已寻回珠宝蛋
l mean, after all, you do have the egg.
没错  但我们并没有全部的答案
True. But we don't have all the answers.
倘若要争论的话  我不想说话
Well, supposing, for argument's sake, l don't feel like talking?
放心  你会说的
Don't worry, you will.
让我猜猜看
Let me guess.
夹棍及烙铁
Thumbscrews and hot coals.
不  我们的方法比较先进
Hardly. We're much more sophisticated than that.
- 戊硫代巴比妥钠？ - 太过粗糙  非常不可靠
- Sodium Pentothal? - A bit crude. Very unreliable.
我们比较喜欢番木鳖毒
We prefer curare with
混合强效迷幻药
an effective psychedelic compound.
保证有效
Guaranteed results.
但会导致脑部永久性伤害
- But with permanent brain damage.
不幸的副作用
- An unfortunate side effect.
我们的名菜之一
One of our specialities.
馅料酿羊头
Stuffed sheep's head.
很奇怪
lt's odd,
但在我被盯着看时 胃口尽失
but when l'm stared at l seem to lose my appetite.
谢谢你的晚餐
Oh, thank you for dinner.
那么就明天见了
Until tomorrow, then.
我要道晚安了
- Well, l'll say good night.
我倒是可以进去喝杯睡前酒
- l could come in for a nightcap.
或许改天吧
Some other time, perhaps.
你要来杯睡前酒吗？不必了
l don't suppose you'd care for a nightcap? No.
想必你航程愉快吧？
l trust you had a pleasant flight.
请跟我来  一切已准备妥当
lf you step this way, l think you will find everything is in order.
我要感谢你们工匠的精湛手艺
Congratulations on the quality of your workmanship, Kamal Khan.
- 卡马汗王子 - 谢谢你  奥洛夫将军
Thank you, General Orlov.
每个部分都根据蓝金提供的规格
As you can see, each piece has been meticulously duplicated
予以严谨地复制
according to Lenkin's specifications.
很好！
Good.
把它放上直升机
Have it put aboard the helicopter.
能信任他们吗？
- Can they be trusted?
我保证他们会三缄其口
- l assure you oftheir silence.
我们两人都下了极大的赌注
We are both playing for enormous stakes.
我得到我想要的
l get what l want,
你得到真的珠宝
then you get the genuine jewellery.
一点不错
Exactly...
精确的时间控制非常重要
The precise timing will be essential.
记住  不可改变计划
Remember: nothing must be changed.
一周后的今天
One week from today,
在卡马克斯城
in Karl-Marx-Stadt.
- 卡马克斯城 - 没错
- Karl-Marx-Stadt. - Correct.
都处理好了？
- Everything taken care of?
照你的吩咐办好了  阁下
- As you ordered, Excellence.
所以  你取回珠宝蛋了
- So, you recovered it?
从一个窃贼手中
- From an accomplice ofthe thief.
马上把他杀了
He must be eliminated at once.
当然
不准再有安全上的漏洞
There must be no further security breach.
这个膺品已引起不少麻烦
This fake has caused enough trouble.
我要走了
l must go.
我对你的表现很满意
Everything has been most satisfactory.
奥洛夫将军  你太客气了
Most kind, General Orlov.
去杀了邦德
Get Bond.
那个英国人脱逃了
The Englishman has escaped.
他跑不远的  我们会去追踪他
He won't go very far. We'll track him.
很好  运动开始
Good. Let the sport commence.
拦住他…
Head him off.
坐下
Sit!
找到他了！…
We have him.
围住他！…
Go round.
他在那里！
He's in there.
不要出声
Hiss off.
断他后路！别让他跑了
Don't let him get away.
停船！
老兄  上来
C'mom, buddy, c'mon.
- 让些空间给他 - 谢谢
- 你还好吗？ - 我很好
- Hey, you all right, buddy? - l'm fine.
- 你是我们这一团的吗？ - 不  女士  我是经济团的
- Are you with our group? - No, ma'am. l'm with the economy tour.
邦德先生实在是稀有动物
Mr Bond is indeed a very rare breed.
不过马上就要绝种了
Soon to be made extinct.
照相
我要那个包头巾男子的照片 太棒了
属毒章鱼
Genus Hapalochlaena.
他的毒液可在数秒内致人于死
Produces a venom that's invariably fatal in seconds.
游艇上就有这种旗帜
The barge had that sign.
是一个住在 水上宫殿的富家女所拥有
lt belongs to a wealthy woman who lives on the floating palace.
- 她是谁？ - 没有人知道她的真实姓名
Who?No one knows her real name,
大家都叫她「八爪女」
but she's known as Octopussy.
我在卡马汗那里听过这名字
That's the name l heard at Kamal's.
听说岛上全是美女 不准男人进入
l hear that island's full of beautiful women. No men allowed.
真的？性别歧视
Really? Sexual discrimination.
我一定要亲自拜访一下
l'll definitely have to pay it a visit.
晚安
Good evening.
我正在猜你何时会到
l wondered when you might arrive.
你就是神秘的八爪女
So you are the mysterious Octopussy.
你就是詹姆斯邦德
And you are James Bond.
007  杀人执照
007, licensed to kill.
我是你今晚的目标吗？
Am l to be your target for tonight?
不完全是
Not necessarily.
要看你告诉我多少 有关走私珠宝
Depends how much you tell me about jewellery smuggling.
及我方情报员 在东柏林被杀的事
And why one of our agents was killed in East Berlin.
我什么都不知道
l know nothing about that.
你记得或斯特史迈上校吗？
You remember Major Dexter Smythe?
你奉命逮捕他  对不对？
You were sent out to arrest him, weren't you?
你了解的真不少
You seem to have done your homework.
谢谢  我当然记得 史迈在光荣退伍后
Thank you. Yes. Smythe, after a brilliant military career,
便加入我方情报组织
joined our secret service.
他的任务是找回 落入北韩手中的一批中国黄金
His mission was to recover a cache of Chinese gold, seized in North Korea.
他与当地向导双双失踪
Both he and his native guide disappeared.
黄金从此也消失无踪
The gold was never found.
二十年后  你奉命抓他归案
And 20 years later you were sent after him.
向导的尸体被人发现
The guide's body turned up with a bullet
头颅中有来自史迈左轮枪的子弹
still in his skull from Smythe's revolver.
我在斯里兰卡找到他 劝他面对事实
l traced Smythe to Sri Lanka,
在我逮捕他前 我给他24小时处理私人事务
and gave him 24 hours to clear up his affairs before l took him back.
他宁可选择自杀 也不愿面对军事审判的耻辱
He committed suicide rather than face the disgrace of a court martial.
这有何关连？
What's the connection?
他是我父亲
He was my father.
我一直希望命运能让我俩见面
l'd hoped fate would bring us together one day.
替他报仇？
To avenge him?
不  为了感谢你让他光荣地死去
To thank you for giving him an honourable alternative.
进来
Come in.
卡马汗要见你
Kamal Khan to see you.
邦德逃脱了
Bond has escaped.
- 你真大意 - 我道歉
- How careless of you. - l apologise.
卡马汗  见见我的新客人
By the way, l'd like you to meet my new house guest.
可以说是这个家族的老朋友
An old friend of the family, you might say.
真好
How lovely.
你求生存的方式真讨厌
You have a nasty habit of surviving.
你也知道适者生存
You know what they say about the fittest.
八爪女  我会很高兴…
Octopussy, l'd enjoy
能再有一个亲自解决他的机会
another opportunity to take care of Mr Bond personally.
我自己会处理邦德先生
l will take care of Mr Bond myself.
晚安
Good night.
好好享受
And enjoy yourselves.
邦德先生
Mr Bond.
我父亲成为章鱼教的权威
My father became a leading authority on octopi.
他深爱他们
He loved them.
他昵称我叫八爪女
His pet name for me was Octopussy.
邦德先生  走私不关情报局的事
Mr Bond, smuggling is no concern of the secret service.
我并未触犯英国法律
l've violated no British law.
你随时可以离去
You are free to leave,
但是我希望你能留下来作客几天
but l'd much prefer if you stayed as my guest for a few days.
我的荣幸
l'd like that.
关德琳  带邦德先生到他的房间
Gwendoline, show Mr Bond to his room.
晚安  邦德先生
Good night, Mr Bond.
明早见
Till the morning, then.
梅姬
Midge.
好好招呼邦德先生 但先加倍他房间的警卫
Extend Mr Bond every courtesy, but double the guard on his quarters.
是  夫人
他说岛上戒备森严
He says the island is heavily guarded.
我们不想与八爪女为敌
We don't want to make enemies with the woman.
绝不能伤到那个女人
The woman must not be harmed.
当我父亲的黄金用完后
When Father's gold ran out,
当初在香港替他卖掉黄金的人
the people in Hong Kong who'd disposed of it for him
提供我走私钻石的任务
offered me a commission to smuggle some diamonds.
我发现我是个中好手
l discovered l had a talent for it.
所以你就加入这一行
You went into business for yourself?
是  但我需要一个组织 所以我重建了古老的章鱼教
Yes, but l needed an organisation, so l revived the old Octopus cult.
那么你又是从哪里 找到这么多美女？
Well, then. Where did you recruit all these lovelies?
东南亚有许多这类型的人
There are many of them all over Southeast Asia,
寻求精神导师及心灵修炼 谁知道到底是什么
looking for a guru, spiritual discipline, who knows what.
我训练她们
l train them.
给她们姊妹情谊的目标 及物质享受的生活
Give them a purpose, a sisterhood and a way of life.
- 藉由犯罪行为 - 藉由商业行为
- ln crime? - ln business.
我采多角经营 航运、饭店与巡回马戏团
l have diversified into shipping, hotels, carnivals and circuses.
- 他还在岛上吗？ - 开玩笑
- ls he still there? - You must be joking.
007在一座美女如云的岛上？
007 on an island populated exclusively by women?
不到早上是见不到他的
We won't see him till dawn.
- 我午夜再来换班 - 没问题
- l'll relieve you at midnight. - No problem.
我们要去哪里吗？
Are we going somewhere?
我明天要去欧洲洽谈商务
l have to go to Europe tomorrow on a business trip.
真可惜  我正准备好好享受一下
Oh, that's a pity. l was just beginning to enjoy myself.
我想你该留下来  我只去一周
l think you should stay. l'll only be gone a week.
等我回来再讨论未来的计划
When l come back we'll discuss the future.
我不能保证我还会待在这里
Well, l can't guarantee that l'll be here when you return.
詹姆斯  我们是同一类的人
Oh, James. We're two of a kind.
以你的聪明才智 如果愿意冒险的话
There are vast rewards for a man of your talents willing
绝对能发财
to take risks.
我不愿被人雇用
- l'm not for hire.
好一个有原则的男人 但有人悬赏你
- A man of principle. With a price on his head.
你当然是为女皇及国家办事
Naturally, you would do it for Queen and country.
我没有国家  也没有人悬赏我
l have no country, l have no price on my head.
我这样的人不需要向你这个 受雇的杀手道歉
l don't have to apologise to you, a paid assassin, for what l am.
不要！
No.
你说的不错  我们是同一类的人
You're right. We are two of a kind.
詹姆斯！
James.
Q  是你吗？
Q?
有什么不对吗？
ls something wrong?
没什么  只是种感觉
Not really. Just a feeling.
何不回到床上来？
Why don't you come back to bed?
快躲开！
Move!
James.
小心！
Watch it!
快走！
Come on.
小心！
Careful.
把枪给我
The gun!
维杰怎么了？
What happened to Vijay?
- 我发现他时他还活着 - 他有没有说什么？
He was alive when l found him.
他只说是卡马汗的人
- Did he say anything? - Only ''lt was Kamal's men.''
再也没有问题了
No more problems.
通知M在柏林与我会合
- Better signal M to meet me in Berlin.
为什么？
- Why?
我要到卡马克斯城的马戏团
Well, l have to go to a circus in Karl-Marx-Stadt.
我们证实了009被杀时 八爪女的马戏团也在东柏林
We verified the Octopussy Circus was in East Berlin when we lost 009.
卡马克斯城在更东边
Karl-Marx-Stadt is further east.
奥洛夫将军为何要参与犯罪？
Why would General Orlov participate in a jewellery caper?
我认为那批珠宝… 请不要介意我的比喻
Well, the jewellery, sir, l think is, if you'll forgive the analogy,
只是章鱼触须的一小部分
only the tip of the tentacle.
这是你需要的证明文件
Here's the lD you'll need.
查尔斯摩顿 来自里兹制造商的代表
Charles Moreton, manufacturer's representative from Leeds
去考察东德的家俱工厂
visiting furniture factories in East Germany.
- 卡尔会带你进入东德 - 包在我身上
- Karl will take you in. - No problem.
007  记住  全靠你自己了
Remember, 007, you're on your own.
谢谢你  长官  我倍感安慰
Thank you, sir. That's a great comfort.
（各位已离开美军管制区）
Mischka.
（八爪女国际马戏团）
你一定认识柏屈同志 爱尔米塔什博物馆馆长
Of course you know Comrade Borchoi, the curator of the Hermitage.
这才从列宁格勒送来
He just arrived from Leningrad.
罗曼诺夫之星
The Romanov Star.
他们替货车换轨时 你留在这里看守珠宝
Stay here with the jewellery while they switch the car to the main track.
你也留下
You stay, also.
十万吨核爆能量
100 kiloton yield.
与美国中型核弹的威力无法区分
The effects are indistinguishable from the American medium-yield bomb.
引爆装置  仔细听好
The detonator, now listen carefully.
已设定好四小时后引爆
lt is pre-set for a four-hour delay.
在这里设定引爆时间
Set time for the explosion here.
要启动引爆装置
To activate,
插入弹体
insert and twist
顺时钟转四分之一圈
the lever a quarter-turn clockwise.
引爆时至少要离开二十哩
Be at least 20 miles away when it goes off, hm?
（西德费尔德 美国空军基地）
这些珠宝在苏黎也 可为我们赚进三亿美金 300 million in Z黵ich.
The jewellery should net us
我们还是得先越过边界
We still have to cross the border.
我该走了
l must go.
小姐  再见  祝好运
Au revoir, dear lady. Good luck.
把那筒子拿过来
Bring the canister.
放到车上
Put it in the car.
- 别管它了  走吧 - 我们留下来
Leave that. Let's go.Let's stay.
坐在箱子上  双手放在膝盖上 动作快点
Sit on that box. Hands on your knees. Come on, move.
为何把核弹装在火车上？
Why is that bomb on the train?
- 你是谁？ - 英国情报员
- Who are you? - British secret service.
你应该更担心要如何活着离开
You should be more concerned about getting out of here alive.
我更关心美国空军基地内
l am more concerned about an atomic
即将引爆的核弹
bomb exploding on a US Air Force base.
你当然不是想桃起核战
You can't be inviting a nuclear war.
万一美国报复呢？
What happens when the US retaliates?
向谁报复？
Against whom?
天啊  当然了
My God. Of course.
我方的早期预警系统
Our early-warning system will rule out the bomb having come from Russia
会排除遭受苏俄 或其他国家攻击的可能性
or anywhere else.
所有人都会误认为…
Everyone will assume incorrectly that
是美国的核弹意外引爆所致
it was a US bomb triggered accidentally.
那是最合理的解释了
That would be the most plausible explanation.
欧洲就会实施片面限武裁军
Europe will insist on disarmament,
使别国国境毫无防御措施 让你的军队如入无人之境
leaving every border undefended for you to walk across at will.
成千上万无辜百姓死于非命
lt doesn't matter a damn to you
对你是一点关系也没有
that thousands of innocent people will die in your accident.
总比那些在莫斯科的老政客
Better than letting a handful of old men in Moscow
在谈判中丧失优势要好的多
bargain away our advantage in disarmament talks.
将军  站起来  你要去阻止火车
On your feet, General. You're going to stop that train.
- 太迟了 - 你可以在边界拦下火车
- Too late. - You can stop it at the border.
杀了他！…
Kill him!
到火车站去！
Get to the station!
拦住那部车！
Stop that car!
停下来！
Stop.
跟着那部车
Follow that car.
卡马汗叫我们留在这里 直到越过边界
Kamal Khan says we are to stay here until we cross the border.
是奥洛夫将军的车
The licence plate is General Orlov's.
我们发现这个
We have discovered this.
奥洛夫将军在哪里？
- Where is General Orlov now?
据报他正前往边界
- Last reported heading for the border.
我要到那列火车上！
l must get to that train.
Stop!
卑劣的小偷
A common thief.
侮辱了身上的军服
A disgrace to the uniform.
没错  但是明天…
Yes. But tomorrow...
我将成为英雄
l shall be a hero...
苏联的大英雄
of the Soviet Union.
现在是11点45分 表演在三点开始
lt is now 1 1 .45. The performance begins at 3.
预留表演延迟的时间 核弹设定在3点45分引爆
Allowing for delays, set the bomb to detonate at 3.45.
我们一定要在 3点15分前离开基地
We must leave the base by 3.1 5.
我想你们都不会迟到
l take it none of you will be late.
- 去看好珠宝！ - 你认出他是谁吗？
The jewellery. - Did you recognise him? - No.
不  陪着她
Stay here with her.
车项上有麻烦
On the roof. Trouble.
Mischka.
这一刀…
And this...
为我的兄弟报仇
for my brother.
这是为009报仇
And that's for 009.
戈宾达会看着珠宝
Gobinda will stay with the jewellery.
将军  失陪一下 我要去安排行程
General, excuse me. l have some travel arrangements to make.
- 好好享受表演 - 谢谢
Enjoy the show. - Thank you.
将军一定会乐死了
- l'm sure he'll get a big blast out of this.
我相信他不会失望的
l know he won't be disappointed.
（空军基地）
- 是邦德 - 很好  让他去
- That was Bond. - Good. Let him keep going.
他一定来不及 顺便连他也一起除掉
He'll be late and we'll be rid of him too.
棒极了  对不对？
Great, isn't it?
太棒了
Fantastic.
- 真精彩 - 将军
- Marvellous. - General...
若我偷你的皮夹要禁闭多久？
How long would l get in the brig if l stole your wallet?
- 大概两年 - 要这么久？
- About two years. - That long?
既然如此  我最好还给你
Well, in that case, l'd better return it.
你这个小坏蛋
Son of a gun.
（费尔德美国空军基地）
指挥官在哪里？这是紧急事件
- Where's the Base Commander? - Let's see your circus pass.
- 请出示你的马戏团通行证 - 该死  我说过是紧急事件
Damn it, man, it's urgent.
下车  双手举起来
Get out. Hands up!
上尉  有个疯子开赃车闯了进去
Some nut in a red shirt went through in a stolen car.
他指名找指挥官  穿件红衬衫
Wants the Base Commander.
他在那里！
There he is.
那个穿红衬衫的家伙  快去抓他
Go after that guy in the red shirt. Behind the trailers.
大伙儿继续找  他一定在附近
Keep searching, you guys. He's gotta be around here somewhere.
拖车底下也要搜查
Look under the trailer, you guys.
快  动作快
各位女士先生  请注意
- Ladies and gentlemen...
- 还有别人在里面吗？ - 本团首度在贵国献艺…
- Hey. ls anyone else in there? For the first time in this country,
桃战死亡极限的人肉炮弹
the death-defying human cannonball.
非常荣幸向各位介绍…
l have the pleasure in presenting to you
勇敢无畏的法兰西斯柯
Francisco the Fearless.
那个人穿了小丑的服装
The suspect's wearing a clown suit. Over.
就是他！
That's him.
老兄  等一下  跟我们走
Hold it, buddy. You're coming with us.
将军  大炮里有核弹
- General, there's a bomb in that cannon.
当然  要不然该放哪里？
- Sure. Where else would a bomb be?
- 老套的小丑把戏 - 我说真的  我是英国情报员
- Great clown. - l'm deadly serious. l'm a British agent.
- 什么？ - 告诉他我是谁
- What? - For God's sake, tell him who l am.
卡马汗和奥洛夫骗了你 我看见他们把珠宝拿走了
Kamal and Orlov double-crossed you. l saw them take the jewellery off the train.
你相信了吧？
Does that convince you?
核弹设定在3点45分引爆 只剩下90秒
Sir, that bomb is set to explode at 3.45. That's 90 seconds from now.
将军  他不是醉了就是疯子
General, this man's either
大家快让开
drunk or crazy.
他会毁了整个行动
He'll destroy the entire operation.
放开我…
你们两个快抓住他
You two, grab that man. Hold him.
- 抓住他 - 该死！快放手
Damn it. Let go.
放开我  那里面有炸弹
Let me go, there's a bomb in there.
放开他
Let him go.
大家安静
Quiet, everyone.
现在吗？
Now?
非常谢谢你  你做得很好
Thank you. Great job, sir.
卡马汗去哪了？
Where was Kamal going?
回印度了
Back to lndia.
各位观众  刚才出了点紧急状况 不过已经没事了
Folks, we've had an emergency, but everything is all right now.
你们大家都很安全
You and your families are safe.
请各位依序慢慢出场
Now, please leave the tent in an orderly manner.
- 谢谢 - 你表现得太好了
Thank you.
- 飞机加好油了 - 我们一早就离开
- The plane is refuelled. - We'll take off at sunrise.
- 金卷都装上飞机了吗？ - 是的  阁下
- Are the gold certificates on board? - Yes, Excellence.
这些也一起带走 美金、英镑、法郎、马克
We'll take these also. Dollars, pounds, francs, marks.
我可以自己印钞票
l can always print my own.
- 是什么声音？ - 女孩们在勾引男人
- What is that? - Girls selling themselves.
很好  够他们忙一阵子了
Good. lt will keep the men occupied.
我不想让他们见到我离开
l don't want them to see me leave.
过来
跳
Now.
帮我一下
Give us a hand.
快来
Come on.
- 快来 - 都摆平了？
Let's go. All set?
举起来
Lift.
就是这样  稳住
That's it. Steady.
确定马匹都装上马鞍
- Make sure the horses are saddled. - Yes, Excellence.
- 是  阁下 - 我等一下与你会合
l'll join you in a few minutes.
你真的以为逃得掉吗？
- Do you really think you can escape me?
奥洛夫背叛了我们
- Orlov betrayed us.
我发誓根本不知道核弹的事
l swear l knew nothing about the bomb.
我们是伙伴  是朋友
We're partners, we're friends.
八爪女  我绝不会伤害你的
Octopussy, l would never do anything to hurt you.
你想让我与成千上万无辜百姓 一齐被炸死
You left me to be killed along with thousands of innocent people.
八爪女…
Octopussy. Octopussy.
你看  我要把这带给你
Look. l was bringing you this.
我们能发大财
We can make millions.
拿下她  她是我们的护身符
Take her. She's our ticket out of here.
Q  想必你能操纵这玩意儿
- l trust you can handle this contraption. - lt goes by hot air.
- 全靠热气 - 那你就行了
Oh, then you can.
- 她们似乎已控制住情况 - 我没看见八爪女
- They're doing fine. - But l don't see Octopussy.
- 她在那里  她有麻烦了 - 把你的臭手拿开
- There she is. She's in trouble. - Get your hands off me.
- 我把气球降下去 - 不  上升
- l'll take her down. - No. Up!
你要去哪里？
Where are you going?
别笨了  007  快回来
Look, don't be an idiot, 007. Come back.
杀了他
Kill him.
快点！…
Come on.
你们想干嘛？别闹了 我们没时间瞎搅和
What are you doing? Cut it out. We haven't time for that.
- 帅哥！ - 或许等一下
Later perhaps.
快跑！
Come on. Giddap.
快！
Come on.
他会害死大家  出去杀了他
He'll kill us all. Go out and get him.
- 出去外面？ - 快去！
- Out there? - Go.
是  阁下
Yes, Excellence.
抓稳了  快跳！
Jump!
我国政府坚决否认 此一事件曾经发生过
My government categorically denies the incident ever occurred.
然而  我们要求邦德…
However, we request Bond to return one of our most historic treasures -
归还我国的历史国宝 罗曼诺夫之星
the Romanov Star.
考量英俄双边关系
ln the interests of our Anglo-Soviet relationships, t
我相信这是可以安排的
hat can be arranged.
邦德指挥官在哪里？
Where is Commander Bond?
很不幸地  由于他受了重伤
Owing to the serious nature of his injuries,
目前仍不适合旅行
he's still not fit enough to travel.
一…二…
ln. Out. ln. Out.
- 我希望… - 什么？
- l wish... - What?
真希望你的身体不是那么虚弱
l wish you weren't in such a weakened condition.
詹姆斯！
James!
（詹姆斯邦德会在）
FROM A VIEW TO A KILL 再度现身）